Roberto

Diaz Morales



Contact

Address:

Torquemada 27 2º 2 28043 Madrid Spain

Phone:

+34 657047430

Email:

rober.diaz@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertodiazmorales/

Github:

https://github.com/RobeDM

Hobbies

- Machine Learning competitions
- Mountain Bike
- Climbing

Summary

I am passionate about Artificial Intelligence. During my professional career, I have applied machine learning and deep learning on a wide variety of areas. I have a wide experience in applying these techniques, from traditional machine learning techniques to state of art Deep Learning architectures.

I am currently the head of the Machine Learning department at Treelogic and also Adjunct Professor in the University Carlos III de Madrid, where I teach some courses related with machine learning and computer vision. This combination of research in academia and industry has oriented my career to solve real problems.

Experience

Treelogic - 2015 to Currently **Head of Machine Learning Unit**

- Definition and technical management of AI solutions.
- Development of advanced artificial intelligence solutions.

Accenture Analytics - 2014 to 2015 Data Scientist

• Development of advanced artificial intelligence solutions.

University Carlos III de Madrid - 2008 to 2014 **Researcher**

• Development of advanced artificial intelligence solutions.

Sun Microsystems - 2005 to 2008 **Software Developer**

Software Developer.

Telefónica R&D - 2003 to 2005 Intern

• Software Developer.

Teaching Experience

University Carlos III de Madrid - 2018 to Currently

• Adjunct Professor.

KSchool - 2016 to 2018

• Teaching "Machine Learning with Python" in the Master Program "Big Data Architecture"

University Carlos III de Madrid - 2008 to 2014 **Researcher**

• Development of advanced artificial intelligence solutions.

Education

2016 - Phd in Machine Learning - University Carlos III de Madrid

- <u>Department</u>: Signal Theory and Communications.
- <u>Thesis Title</u>: Efficient Parallel Implementation of Kernel Methods.

2010 - MsC focused on Machine Learning - University Carlos III de Madrid

• <u>Department</u>: Signal Theory and Communications.

2006 - Telecommunications Engineering: 5 years degree - University Carlos III Madrid

• Thesis Title: Language recognition based on GMMs.

Courses

2021 - Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) specialization

- <u>Certificate</u>: DeepLearning.Al (online)
- Link: https://coursera.org/share/74dfceb3de433b878513f157d5d1963d

2018 - Practical Reinforcement Learning

- <u>Certificate</u>: HSE University (online)
- Link: https://coursera.org/share/133d1794184ccdba2bb4fad6a574202a

2018 - Probabilistic Graphical Models Specialization

- <u>Certificate</u>: Stanford University (online)
- Thesis Title: https://coursera.org/share/9939bcbff05fd8b6b9af7941a2e08271

Machine Learning Prizes

2015 - 3rd Prize in the ICDM 2015 Drawbridge Cross Device Challenge

- Organizer: Kaggle
- Link: https://www.kaggle.com/c/icdm-2015-drawbridge-cross-device-connections
- Interview: http://blog.kaggle.com/2015/09/16/icdm-winners-interview-3rd-place-roberto-

diaz/

2013 - 5th Prize in the III Facebook Competition of Kaggle

- <u>Organizer</u>: Kaggle
- <u>Link</u>: <u>http://www.kaggle.com/c/facebook-recruiting-iii-keyword-e</u>xtraction

2012 - 3th Prize in the EMC Data Science Challenge

- <u>Organizer</u>: Kaggle
- Link: http://www.kaggle.com/c/emc-data-science

2012 - 9th Prize in the I Facebook Competitionj of Kaggle

- Organizer: Kaggle
- Link: http://www.kaggle.com/c/FacebookRecruiting

Published research Papers, Books and Chapters

More than 20 research papers in the Machine Learning area published in JCR journals, conferences or book chapters. The complete list can be found here:

https://scholar.google.es/citations?user=qwsmJyMAAAAJ&hl=es